Guide to the Class of 1942, Yale College, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Class of 1942, Yale College, records
1942-2002
RU 27
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
2
3 boxes
18.8
The records consist of class notes, correspondence, minutes, photographs, and other records concerning reunions, donations, meetings, and other activities of the Yale College Class of 1942.
Yale College (1887- ). Class of 1942
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 10-A (YRG 10-A), Records of Yale College classes.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records were transferred from the Association of Yale Alumni (AYA), 1993.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is partially restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Original born digital files, as well as preservation masters, may not be accessed due to their fragility. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist request that they be made. Born digital files cannot be accessed remotely. System requirements include a Manuscripts and Archives computer and file viewing software.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of class notes, correspondence, minutes, photographs, and other records concerning reunions, donations, meetings, and other activities of the Yale College Class of 1942.
Class reunions; Photographs; Yale College (1887- ). Class of 1942; Yale University -- Alumni and alumnae
- Records of the Class of 1942, 1942-2001; Accession 1994-A-037
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2036
  - Financial Records, 1967-1972 (Box 1)
  - Yearbook, Pledges, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Endowments, Pledges, 1991-1992 (Box 1)
  - Class Dues, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Minutes, Agendas, Constitution, 1968-1977 (Box 1)
  - Meetings
    - 1958 (Box 1)
    - 1959 (Box 1)
    - 1960 (Box 1)
    - 1961 (Box 1)
    - 1962 (Box 1)
  - Class Officers
    - 1969-1971 (Box 1)
    - 1968-1969 (Box 1)
  - Class Officers, Reports (Annual), 1966-1967, 1961-1962 (Box 1)
  - Class Dinner and Parties, 1967-1972 (Box 1)
  - Class Dinner Cuban Discussion, Correspondence, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Atkinson, Correspondence, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Obituaries, McCorkle Correspondence, 1992 (Box 1)
  - General Correspondence
    - 1967-1972 (Box 1)
    - 1992-1993 (Box 1)
  - Executive Committee
    - 1971-1972 (Box 2)
    - 1967-1971 (Box 2)
  - Executive Board, 1990-1992 (Box 2)
  - Executive Committee, 1991-1992 (Box 2)
  - Treasurer's Reports, Exec. Committee, 1992 (Box 2)
  - Executive Committee, 1991-1993 (Box 2)
  - Published Class Notes, 1942-1968 (Box 2)
  - Class Notes
    - 1970 (Box 2)
    - 1970-1971 (Box 2)
  - Class Notes - in progress and completed, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
  - Class Notes
    - 1978-1992 (Box 2)
    - 1987-1992 (Box 2)
  - Class Awards, 1982, 1984 (Box 2)
  - Yale Alumni Magazine, 1992 (Box 2)
  - First Reunion, 1947 (Box 2)
  - Twenty-fifth Reunion, 1967 (Box 2)
  - Twenty-fifth Reunion, Exhibition, 1967 (Box 2)
  - Thirtieth Reunion, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
  - Fiftieth Yearbook, 1988-1992 (Box 2)
  - Fiftieth Reunion Fund
    - 1988-1989 (Box 2)
    - 1990-1992 (Box 2)
- Minutes and letters [computer files], 2001-2002; Accession 2002-A-201
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2037
  - Minutes of the Yale 1942 Executive Committee, 2001 October 25; computer file (DOC)
  - Letter to Dean Richard H. Brodhead from David S. Atkinson, Secretary, Yale 1942, 2002 May 10; computer file (DOC)
    General note
    Contact Public Services (phone: 203 432-1735, e-mail: mssa.reference@yale.edu) for information on accessing this digital object.
- "Countdown to Reunion", 2002; Accession 2002-A-207 (Box 2)
  Original born digital files, as well as preservation masters, may not be accessed due to their fragility. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist request that they be made. Born digital files cannot be accessed remotely. System requirements include a Manuscripts and Archives computer and file viewing software.
  - "Countdown to Reunion," website for the Class of 1942's 60th reunion, 2002; computer files (HTML, JPEG, DOC, RTF, WPD)
    - Hard copy (Box 1)